<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://macdonaldster.ca/feed/pages.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://macdonaldster.ca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-03-27T09:52:10-06:00</updated><id>http://macdonaldster.ca/feed/pages.xml</id><title type="html">macdonaldster.ca | Pages</title><subtitle>A personal site, not a blog</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Weight</title><link href="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2021-03-11.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Weight" /><published>2021-03-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-03-11T06:11:00-07:00</updated><id></id><content type="html" xml:base="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2021-03-11.html"># The Weight

I feel like if I post this to Twitter or something, it will not be received in the spirit I am sharing it with so I'll just leave it here and hope someone sees it.

Turns out we all like music. Now, on Twitter, someone will say &quot;yeah, you mean rich, privledged people like music&quot;, and then someone else will say &quot;how come there are no X people in the video&quot; and so on. Just watch and enjoy it.

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ph1GU1qQ1zQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="movies" /></entry><entry><title type="html">No More Smartwatch?</title><link href="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/no-smart-watch-2021-02-26.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No More Smartwatch?" /><published>2021-02-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-02-26T06:11:00-07:00</updated><id></id><content type="html" xml:base="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/no-smart-watch-2021-02-26.html"># No More Smartwatch? - 2021-02-26 

I recently got tired of the constant interruptions I was experiencing from my smartwatch. This was a very inexpensive Miband 4. It had some odd idiosyncracies, among them was a quick buzz at 10:15pm that I was never able to turn off. I also would get odd notifications and bumps that seemed to be ignorning my settings, etc.

This is not about complaining about Miband 4s. It is also not about how I should spend more on my smart watches if I want something nice. It really is about me realizing my major use of the smartwatch was as a vibrating alarm. I almost never used it to read notifications. I would get a lot of notifications on the watch but most were not important. The ones that were meant I needed to glance at all of them to make sure I was &quot;getting the good ones&quot;.

At some point, I just decided I was done. I dug through my bin of old electronics and found my Timex Expedition Shock (Timex that looks a lot like a Casio G-Shock, has a dark screen, and 3 vibrating alarms, etc). It was still working fine despite not being used in years and took a few minutes to set up to work as needed. I still maintain a series of alarms on my phone in case I miss the wrist vibrations, but I did that with the smartwatches as well.

Finally, I installed an app (Android) called [Buzzkill](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.samruston.buzzkill) that took a while to get set up but is now basically burying all but the most important notifications. I can also make sure I never miss anything from my wife, and my boss can reach me during normal working hours. Other than that, I see notifications only when I look for them. This is great. I barely check my phone now unless I am very bored, or I need it for something. I have definitely but doing a lot less of the &quot;watch buzzed, missed the notification, pick up phone and scroll&quot; behaviour.

We'll see how it goes but I don't see myself going back to a smart watch for a while, if at all, at this time.</content><author><name></name></author><category term="organizing" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Blues Brothers Is About Faith</title><link href="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2021-02-13.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Blues Brothers Is About Faith" /><published>2021-02-13T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-02-13T06:11:00-07:00</updated><id></id><content type="html" xml:base="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2021-02-13.html"># The Blues Brothers Is About Faith - 2021-02-13 

During the movie The Blues Brothers, Elwood says several times that they are &quot;on a mission from god&quot;. It is clear, at the end of the movie in the incredible chase from the concert hall that he and, presuably, Jake believe this. There is absolutely no way they should have made it, but Elwood, with his characteristic unflappability drives that car as if it is on a rail through every possible obstacle.

They have an unshakeable faith that God is real, God is involved, and God is ensuring they get the taxes paid for the orphanage. It's beautiful.

Now, I don't share that faith, possibly because I wasn't raised by a nun in an orphanage, but it is a great conceit for the movie and I never really fully understood it before. I have watched the movie several times in the past thinking it was portraying the brothers as Fonzie-style, ultra cool, jaded super heroes. But really, it is the hand of Fate we see, and they are just going with it.

This wouldn't be a blog post without me going on about my personal feelings on the matter. I really do long for a universe where good is rewarded, and everything has meaning, but I think really we are living in a universe where chains of causality stretch back into the first events of the universe, and roll out to the last. We are sitting on a slice of a causality chain and have no more control over the next instant than we do over the proverbial butterfly flapping its wings over Chile causing a hurricaine to roar up the East Coast of North America.

What comforts me is that we can't seem to maintain realizations about the true nature of reality for more than an instant. Maybe, through meditation practice, we can hold onto it for more time but really, it is never all the time for most people. And when you aren't seeing it, you are living in what most would call the real world. You are concerned about your life, you want to do well, you are making decisions, and they feel like real choices. Without this, what motivation would we have to go on. When people talk about conciousness as an evolutionary advantage that emerged from the biology, I don't disagree. I think our ability to be lost in the moment, unable to maintain a long term perspective, forgetting the hardest parts of the past, this is what allows us to go on.</content><author><name></name></author><category term="movies" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2021-02-09 Blog</title><link href="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2021-02-09.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021-02-09 Blog" /><published>2021-02-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-02-09T06:11:00-07:00</updated><id></id><content type="html" xml:base="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2021-02-09.html"># 2021-02-09 Blog

Just listened to some of the Republican impeachment lawyers after work while I did some stuff around the house. I can't tell if they are morons or think we are.

They made a number of arguments that contradicted other arguments they had made. They are also ignoring the fact that Trump was impeached prior to leaving office. This is completely disingenuous. Finally, when that lawyer was tearing up while reading that completely unnecessary Longfellow poem, all I could think of was how the Right is going to make fun of Raskin for his genuine emotion, while lauding that moron for his.

Oh, and that first guy basically going on forever about how elections are the remedy for unfit Presidents. He drove the point home over and over that the people recognized Trump was an unfit President and voted him out. What a buffoon. He's getting fired, soon, probably. Not only did he go out of his way to explain the President soundly lost the election, he also hammered home the point that it was because the American people thought he was unfit for office. It's hilarious. That is exactly why he is being impeached. Trump will be furious that this was a position taken by his own lawyer.</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="politics" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2021-02-08 Blog</title><link href="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2021-02-08.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021-02-08 Blog" /><published>2021-02-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-02-08T06:11:00-07:00</updated><id></id><content type="html" xml:base="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2021-02-08.html"># 2021-02-08 Blog

I have moved the site to be self-hosted, away from Github pages. I found trying to add features to the site was cumbersome and it takes a while for the system to refresh when you commit an edit so trying this for a while.

It is using my hard-coded IP so hopefully I can stay on top of that.

&lt;b&gt;Later...&lt;/b&gt;

What is the value in writing for public consumption? Is there anything particularly valuable about putting this out in the world versus keeping it to myself?

Well, there is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=rhetorical+triangle&amp;sxsrf=ALeKk034B_pL9nLoqiyysLNAsjTg_Yn3rA:1612847254190&amp;source=lnms&amp;tbm=isch&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjWpKadhNzuAhXO3J4KHS_TBZQQ_AUoAXoECAIQAw&amp;biw=1197&amp;bih=937&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rhetorical Triangle&lt;/a&gt; where we see the three pillars of rhetoric - speaker, message, and audience.

- Speaker - me! I am the speaker - presumably the message, below, is something I want to convey to the audience, also below. In general, people have some kind of agenda.  
- Message - these posts... if you read them, you will find there is not much of value here, just my thoughts. 
- Audience - the reader (in this case, singular, and also me) - it is an empirical that I am the only person that views this site unless I send someone a link.

So, I guess if I were to define my message, it is just sharing of information. I think that information is good, and more is better. Who knows, maybe some programmer with an ostomy who suffers from Ankylosing Spondylitis and has a child and two dogs with their spouse will stumble on this page and discover they have had a kindred spirit out there in the world.

&lt;b&gt;Here is something about programming&lt;/b&gt; - today I spent a ton of time generating emails for someone else to review. The designer who builds the emails can't generate them all himself, so he relies on me to send him the actual emails built from templates he works on to make sure the final round of revisions has everything lined up correctly. Then the QA person also needs to review all these emails. Since the email system is designed to be triggered by complex events in the system, for each email type (e.g. new order, part review) I need to think up a quick and easy way to generate that email without actually compromising the integrity of the test we are trying to run. It is tedious. Even with a bunch of work to make it quick and painless, I am still messing with stuff to trigger the emails. Lesson learned - every system that produces output, should have a way to generate that output so it can be validated. In my case, instead of cobbling together a bunch of SQL scripts to do what I needed (e.g. find orders, etc) I could have made that into a single stored procedure that dumped out the values needed to trigger each type of email and that would be used as input to the email sending code. A couple of hours work, and I can generate all the emails I want with real data.

But, the reality is, I got through today and probably won't need to do it again for a while. Another program that will not be written. :)</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="site" /></entry><entry><title type="html">No Caffeine - 2</title><link href="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2020-09-08-no-caffeine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No Caffeine - 2" /><published>2020-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-09-08T05:11:00-06:00</updated><id></id><content type="html" xml:base="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2020-09-08-no-caffeine.html"># No Caffeine - Day 2

Started the day off with green tea and some Tylenol around 2 hours after being up. I didn't need any after that, although I do have a slight headache now, as I write this just before bed. I ended up having a short nap after work today and then a half cup of coffee. I felt like that late in the day and such a small amount, it would be OK and it is.

My goal isn't to &quot;quit coffee&quot;, it is to reduce caffeine, possibly to zero. Tapering is the recommended method for getting off coffee, and I've used it successfully in the past.

I found my focus at work today was really good and the day passed without anxious moments (e.g. easy to stay on task, no thinking about anything but work). That's great and should help my productivity a little if that is a consistent effect (could just be I had a good day of working).</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="caffeine" /></entry><entry><title type="html">No Caffeine - 1</title><link href="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2020-09-07-no-caffeine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No Caffeine - 1" /><published>2020-09-07T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-09-07T05:11:00-06:00</updated><id></id><content type="html" xml:base="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2020-09-07-no-caffeine.html"># No Caffeine - Day 1

About a week ago, I started getting really brutal headaches. I think they are mild migraines but I've never been diagnosed with them and so I don't go around saying I get them. My mother has been diagnosed as have other family members, though, so I figure it's a safe bet for me.

When I was younger, I would get splitting headaches every single day and was not really given Aspirin, Tylenol, or Advil for them for whatever reason until one day, when I was in my early teens, my family doctor chewed my mother out and insisted she give me something for my headaches if I told her I needed one. I was, and remain, eternally grateful to that man. It made a huge difference to my quality of life.

Now, and for many years, headaches are pretty rare. Maybe the occasional mild one with a cold or flu, and a few times a year a very severe headache that is brutal on day one and tapers off over a couple days. But this new round of headache has lasted longer than before and is reducing in severity much more slowly. When I get like this only Advil and a ton of water plus some quiet (eyes closed) time get me to a place of relief. But that is only sort of working this time.

So a few days pass and I woke up on Saturday morning feeling headache free. Then I had a coffee and within 30 minutes the headache was back. Hm. So, I decided, I'll quit coffee for a while and see if that helps. I've tapered off coffee using green team many times over the course of my life and have that routine down pat so I tried it starting today. So far so good. I do have a mild headache but nothing like the previous days.

I am hoping to journal here regarding my time caffeine free and just see how it goes. I am interest in seeing how my mood, sleep, energy level, and overall health is affected by this.</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="caffeine" /></entry><entry><title type="html">… home</title><link href="http://macdonaldster.ca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="… home" /><published>2020-08-12T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-08-12T06:54:00-06:00</updated><id></id><content type="html" xml:base="http://macdonaldster.ca/">&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;blurb&quot;&gt;
	{% assign sorted = site.pages | sort: 'last_modified_at' | reverse %}
	{% for p in sorted limit:1 %}
		&lt;div&gt;
			{{p.content | markdownify }}
		&lt;/div&gt;
		      &lt;section&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;tags&quot;&gt;
	  {% assign sortedCategories = p.categories  %}
	  {% for category in sortedCategories %}
          &lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;/category/{{ category }}.html&quot;&gt;#{{ category }}&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/span&gt;
	  {% endfor %}
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
      &lt;/section&gt;

 	{% endfor %}
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
	&lt;h1&gt;Notes:&lt;/h1&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;I added category pages to this site so now can refer you to the &lt;a href=&quot;/category/covid19.html&quot;&gt;COVID19&lt;/a&gt; page where I am collecting thoughts on life during this pandemic. &lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;I thought I would stick this link here to remind me why and how to journal - &lt;a href=&quot;https://dariusforoux.com/how-to-journal/&quot;&gt;https://dariusforoux.com/how-to-journal/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;The phrase &quot;isn't there anything faster than a microwave&quot; from The Simpons crosses my mind between 1 and 20 times a day.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Why are we still designing new styles of pants? After all this time, shouldn't we have figured that out?&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
	&lt;h2&gt;Blogs (last updated, first):&lt;/h2&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
	{% assign sorted = site.pages | sort: 'last_modified_at' | reverse %}
	{% for p in sorted %}
	   {% if p.title contains '2020-' or p.title contains '2021-'  %}
	      &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;{{ p.url | absolute_url }}&quot;&gt;{{ p.title }}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	   {% endif %}
 	{% endfor %}
	&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;All other pages (last updated, first):&lt;/h2&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
	{% assign sorted = site.pages | sort: 'last_modified_at' | reverse %}
	{% for p in sorted %}
		{% if p.categories.size &gt; 0  %}
		   {% unless p.categories contains 'blog' %}
	  	      &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;{{ p.url | absolute_url }}&quot;&gt;{{ p.title }} | {{ p.last_modified_at | date: &quot;%Y-%m-%d&quot; }} &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		   {% endunless %}
		{% endif %}
 	{% endfor %}
	&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- /.blurb --&gt;</content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">2020-08-05</title><link href="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2020-08-05-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2020-08-05" /><published>2020-08-05T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-08-05T05:11:00-06:00</updated><id></id><content type="html" xml:base="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2020-08-05-blog.html"># Random Thoughts

OK, I have a few minutes before I go pick up my son from daycare.

Lately, I don't know why I have a web site. I keep thinking there's a reason.

What have been up to?

- we recently took a trip to Calgary, about 3 hours away, using it as a home base to venture into the mountains and also as a delivery location for delicious Calgary BBQ and fried chicken. It was very, very hot there, though, and so we ended up running for cover to our non-AC'd AirBnB which cut some days short and made sleeping a little gross. I did find it very, very restful and relaxing, though, and our dog got to do some swimming, which is really nice.

- writing - I am working on a new short story where this guy is part of a paramilitary force that protects a city from hordes of infected people who are like zombies. It's a zombie story. He's been told these people are not human anymore, that they can never recover from the infection. But, in reality, they can. Discovering this changes everything for him.</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2020-07-21</title><link href="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2020-07-21-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2020-07-21" /><published>2020-07-21T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2020-07-21T05:11:00-06:00</updated><id></id><content type="html" xml:base="http://macdonaldster.ca/pages/2020-07-21-blog.html"># The Trouble With TODO Lists

I just found a TODO list from a few months back. It has a ton of tasks on it that are STILL on my current todo list. They are important tasks. I need to make a Will, for example.

Now, have I done nothing for the last several months? NO. I have done a TON of stuff. What I haven't done is do the things on that list. The things on that list are important but not urgent. 

So this is a &quot;me&quot; problem. When it comes to my personal life, I tread water. I don't build a raft and parlay that into a nice sailing vessel. I tread water. This is why I will never write an novel or successfully organize my tools. My tools are a mess. There are some in the garage, some are in my OFFICE? (WHY?) and some are in my perfectly adaquate tool storage in the basement. I keep my socket set in the garage along with a couple crescent wrenches and screw drivers because they fit my son's bike and some other things. I keep some tools in my office because they are what I frequently need (some more screwdrivers, vice grips, hammer for hanging pictures, grease for hinges, zip ties, etc). Finally, all the heavy duty stuff is in the basement for when I might need it a couple times a year. 

My dream is that they are all in one place, knolled nicely into lined drawers, power tools hung on a peg board, etc. But this will never happen. I would need to plan that out and work on it. And I won't. Instead, I make sure the kitchen is clean and that I get to my doctors appointment. I take care of my sick dog. I play with my son. I work in the garden with my wife. I live. 

Where is the balance? It isn't found in my TODO list. I guess that Will is going to wait for another few months. I hope nothing bad happens in the meantime.</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /></entry></feed>